

Dubai - UAE

□+971 58 575 7397 | ■joorgemelo@gmail.com | ♣jorgeribeiro.github.io | ᡚjorgeribeiro | ₲joorgeribeeiro

"Choose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life."

Summary_

Currently working as a Software Engineer at Privilee. I have worked for the past 8 years as a Full Stack Developer with special interest in backend challenges. The goal of my life is to keep learning new technologies and tools to create and enhance products to improve people's lives. My daily routine is to be an engineer in full time, creating solutions to optimize workflows and contribute to other people's work.

Work Experience _____

Privilee Dubai - UAE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov. 2019 - PRESENT

- · Implementation of new features for our applications: mobile and tablet apps, website and internal management systems.
- Integration of third-party services such as: payment gateways, search engines, CMS and marketing platform.
- Our team work in an Agile environment, going through all the phases suggested by the Scrum framework, constantly refining our backlog and planning all the tasks that will be worked on each sprint.
- Some of the technologies used to build the applications are: PHP, Flutter, Vue.js, React, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, AWS and Docker.
- Our mobile app was awarded as "Dubai's Favourite App" by the public at the 2021 What's On Awards and as "UAE's Favourite App" at the 2022 What's On Awards.

Westwing Brazil Brazil

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Development of a new e-commerce system "WestwingNow" and integrate it with the currently online store "Westwing Club".
- Debugging all the services included in the system in order to analyse its flows.
- · The project is built with Docker, Memcached, RabbitMQ, Solr and Dynamo, PHP, Javascript, Node and MySQL.
- The team worked collaboratively in an Agile environment with all of the tasks defined before each sprint as agreed with the Scrum Master and Product Manager.

Equatorial Energia Group Brazil

Data Scientist Mar. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Automating routines, reports and dashboards with Power BI for the Legal Department.
- Analysing data from internal databases to help attorneys at their decision making.
- Applying Machine Learning techniques (R-Script) to interpret customer behavior.
- Development of applications to improve Tax and Corporate Law workflows and persist their data for further analysis.

Senior Team Projects and Solutions

Brazil Jan 2018-Feb 2019

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

• Development of web applications to the Maranhão Audit Court using Java, EJB, ZK Framework and PostgreSQL.

• Refactored an application called Segurança (Security) that manages employees' user accounts and provides access to internal systems, along with two other team members.

Education

Better Change Academy

Dubai - UAE

CERTIFIED SCRUM PRODUCT OWNER

Jul. 2022

UFMA (Federal University of Maranhão)

Brazil

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Carroll University

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2018
Wisconsin - USA

EXCHANGE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2015 - May. 2016



Heart Disease Classifier

PYTHON, PANDAS, SKLEARN, FLASK, ANGULAR

- Classification of heart disease based on symptoms and personal features. It uses a heart disease dataset from the UCI Machine Learning Repository.
- Source code and description can be found at https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/heart-disease-classifier.

Computer Science Student Classes Planner

LARAVEL, BULMA, SQLITE

- This application helps Computer Science Students from UFMA in the selection of classes in each semester, in order to complete the required hours in less time.
- To check source code and instructions: https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/planejador-cp-ufma.

Meta learning applied to the Problem of Facial Expression Recognition

Python, TensorFlow, Neural Networks, Meta Learning

- Undergraduate thesis developed to become a Computer Scientist bachelor.
- · It uses Convolutional Neural Networks and three datasets to learn emotions from human faces.
- Source code and docs can be found at https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/meta-learning-facial-expression-recognition.

Github Web Scraper

PYTHON, BEAUTIFULSOUP, REQUESTS, PIPENV

- Crawler that gather information about files and sizes of any public Github repository. It creates a tree of files and folders and provides information about percentage of lines of code and bytes.
- Source code and description can be found at https://github.com/jorgeribeiro/github-web-scraper.